Guide to the Tom Burrell papers, 1949-2016 and undated RL.11678
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Tom Burrell papers
1949-2016 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Burrell, Tom
RL.11678
28.0 Linear Feet
Thomas J. Burrell is a Chicago-based advertising executive who started his own advertising agency, Burrell Communications, in 1971. Collection includes clippings, correspondence, texts of presentations, research reports, print advertisements, commercial scripts and storyboards and other printed materials as well as slides, photographs and audiovisual items (videocassettes, optical discs). Professional files reflect Burrell's specialization in advertising to African American and other minority consumer groups and the firm's approach to multicultural marketing. Materials also relate to Burrell's student years as well as notes and drafts of his book, Brainwashed: Challenging the Myth of Black Inferiority and Burrell's nonprofit organization The Resolutions Project. Companies represented include Bell Atlantic, Brown-Forman (Bacardi, Canadian Mist, Jack Daniels), Coca-Cola (including Sprite), K-Mart, McDonald's, Mobil, Philip Morris (Marlboro), Polaroid, Procter & Gamble (Tide, Gain, Crest, others) and Sears. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Client Files; General Files; Presentations and Speeches; Book Files; Personal Files; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Thomas J. Burrell is a Chicago-based advertising executive who started his own advertising agency, Burrell Communications, in 1971.
Born 1939, Chicago; BA English, Roosevelt University 1962; copywriter: Wade Advertising 1960-1964, Leo Burnett 1964-1967, Foote Cone Belding 1967-1968; copy supervisor, Needham Harper Steers 1968-1971; cofounded Burrell McBain agency 1971 with Emmett McBain (change to Burrell Communications 1974); merger with Publicis 2000; Albert Lasker lifetime achievement award 1986; AAF Hall of Fame 2005; published Brainwashed 2010.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced.
Materials may be stored in an offsite facility. Please allow two business days for retrieval. Contact Research Services for further information.
Provenance
The Tom Burrell papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Archie Boston papers
Douglass Alligood papers
Roy Eaton papers
John Benjamin Harris Papers
African American history marketing and promotional posters
J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporation Vertical Files
J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Research Department Records
Collection Overview
Collection includes clippings, correspondence, texts of presentations, research reports, print advertisements, commercial scripts and storyboards and other printed materials as well as slides, photographs and audiovisual items (videocassettes, optical discs). Professional files reflect Burrell's specialization in advertising to African American and other minority consumer groups and the firm's approach to multicultural marketing. Materials also relate to Burrell's student years as well as notes and drafts of his book, Brainwashed: Challenging the Myth of Black Inferiority and Burrell's nonprofit organization The Resolutions Project. Companies represented include Bell Atlantic, Brown-Forman (Bacardi, Canadian Mist, Jack Daniels), Coca-Cola (including Sprite), K-Mart, McDonald's, Mobil, Philip Morris (Marlboro), Polaroid, Procter & Gamble (Tide, Gain, Crest, others) and Sears. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- United States; African Americans -- Race identity; Advertising agencies -- Illinois -- Chicago; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Coca-Cola Company; McDonald's Corporation; Gerber Products Company; Ford Motor Company; General Mills, Inc; Procter & Gamble Company; Sears, Roebuck and Company; Kraft Foods Company; Mobil Oil Corporation; Motorola, Inc; Nabisco, Inc.; Quaker Oats Company; Toyota Motor Sales, U.S.A., Inc.
- Client Files, 1971-2008 and undated; 1
  - General Materials, 1980-2008 and undated; 1
    - Allstate press releases, 2005 (Box 1)
    - American Legacy Foundation news release, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Ariel Capital Management, Inc., 1993-1994 and undated (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Memos, news releases, consumer research and media relations recommendations
    - Art Institute of Chicago press, memos, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Bacardi-Martini U.S.A, Inc., 1997, 2001, 2005 (Box 1)
      Memo, press release, and test results on Bacardi's Fat Joe ad
    - Bell Atlantic, 1997-1998, 2000 and undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
      Memos, news releases, press mentions, notes from ads, photos from ads, second folder contains photos from the "April" TV ad
    - Blockbuster memos, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Brown-Forman Beverage Co., 1984-1993 and undated (Box 1)
      Laminated ads, press mentions, memos regarding Martell cognac, and Canadian Mist
    - Chicago Tribune radio fact sheet for the commercial "Tribune Carol", 1998 (Box 1)
    - Coca-Cola, 1980-2003 and undated; 5 folders (Box 1)
      Advertising fact sheets and storyboards and scripts, photo stills, press mentions, news releases, memos, account files
    - Coca-Cola, 1985-1998 and undated; 5 folders (Box 2)
      Laminated ads, TV commercial storyboards and photos, press mentions for Coke and Sprite products, also includes Minute Maid ad photo stills
    - Coca-Cola--NewsoulofCoke, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
    - Coca-Cola--Sprite, 1987-2000 (Box 2)
    - First Chicago press, memos, 1989-1990 and undated (Box 2)
    - Ford, 1989-1994 and undated (Box 2)
    - General Foods--Stove Top, 1990, 1991, and 1993 (Box 2)
    - General Mills, 1981-2001 (Box 3)
      Includes Bisquick, Cheerios, Hamburger Helper, Kix, Pillsbury. Some ads feature recipes. Also includes press mentions and memos.
    - Gerber press, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Kaiser Foundation HIV Initiative press, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Kellogg's, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
    - Kmart, 1991-1992, 1995 and undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Kraft Maxwell House TV commercial fact sheet, 1996 (Box 3)
    - MARTA press, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
    - McDonald's, 1986-2006; 4 folders (Box 3)
      Miscellaneous materials including clippings, press, campaign with Destiny's Child; Michael Jordan; Black History Month; McNuggets
    - McDonald's, 1986-2006; 9 folders (Box 4)
      press mentions, news releases, memos, TV commercial documents including scripts, photos, storyboards, fact sheets, including ads "Mama's date," "Three little words," "Art Store Break," "Fries spot," "winning face,"
    - McDonald's, 1986-2006; 2 folders (Box 5)
      Includes campaigns with WNBA, Venus and Serena Williams
    - Media Advertising Partnership for a Drug-Free America, 1992-1994 (Box 5)
    - Mobil, 1994-1996; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Motorola, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Nabisco, Inc., 1995 (Box 5)
    - Nationwide Insurance, 1998-1999 (Box 5)
    - Nynex, 1995-1997 and undated (Box 5)
    - Playskool--Kids of Color, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Polaroid Corp., 1993-1995 (Box 6)
    - Procter & Gamble Company, 1990-2009; 5 folders (Box 6)
      Includes Crest, Dance Theater, Pantene
    - Prudential, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Quaker Oats Company, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
    - Sears, 1996-1998 and undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Soft Sheen Products, Inc., 2000 (Box 6a)
    - Stroh Brewery, 1986-1996 and undated (Box 6a)
    - Toyota, 2001-2008 and undated (Box 6a)
    - Verizon, 2000, 2005 and undated (Box 6a)
    - Western Union, 1998 (Box 6a)
    - Zayre, 1987 (Box 6a)
  - Print Advertisements, 1971-2008 and undated; 2
    - Adidas, 2000 (Box 11)
    - Allstate, 2006 (Box 11)
    - Ariel Capital Management, Inc., 1993-1997 (Box 10)
    - Art Institute of Chicago, undated (Box 10)
    - Beatrice, undated (Box 10)
    - Bell South Yellow Pages, 1995-1996 (Box 10)
    - Brown-Forman Beverage Co., 1976-1998; 2 folders (Box 7)
      Includes Bacardi Limon, Canadian Mist, Jack Daniels, Martell, Southern Comfort
    - Brown-Forman Beverage Co.--Canadian Mist, 1974-1989 (Box 11)
    - Burrell Communications self-promotional, undated (Box 10)
    - Coca-Cola, 1974-2000; 5 folders (Box 7)
    - Coca-Cola, 1974-1998; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Coca-Cola--Fresca, Coke, 1992-1994 (Box 13)
    - Coca-Cola--Sprite, 1994-1998 (Box 7)
    - Coca-Cola--Sprite, 1987-1999 (Box 10)
    - First Chicago, 1990 and undated (Box 8)
    - First Union, undated (Box 8)
    - Ford, 1983-1993 (Box 8)
    - Ford, 1983-1993 (Box 10)
    - Ford, 1987 (Box 11)
    - General Mills--Hamburger Helper, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Johnson Products--Afro Sheen, 1978 (Box 13)
    - Kmart, 1994-1996 (Box 8)
    - Kmart, 1993-1994 (Box 11)
    - Kraft--Stove Top, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Kraft--Stove Top, 1994-1995 (Box 11)
    - L'eggs Products, 1994 (Box 8)
    - L'eggs Products, 1994-95 (Box 10)
    - Marlboro, 1971-72 (Box 8)
    - Marlboro, 1971-1972 (Box 10)
    - MARTA, 1988 and undated (Box 11)
    - McDonald's, 1973-2005; 4 folders (Box 8)
    - McDonald's, 1974-2005 (Box 10)
    - McDonald's, 1973-2008; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - McDonald's, 1993-2007 (Box 13)
    - Mobil, 1996 (Box 10)
    - Mobil, 1996-1997 (Box 13)
    - Mobil, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
      Poster for a c ommunity event organized by Mobil and the Detroit Urban League
    - Motorola, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Nielsen Media Research, 2005 (Box 9)
    - Playskool--"Kids of Color", 1993 (Box 9)
    - Polaroid Corp., 1991-1994 (Box 9)
    - Polaroid Corp., 1990-1994 (Box 10)
    - Polaroid Corp., 1994 (Box 12)
    - Procter & Gamble Company, 1993-2005 (Box 9)
      Includes Crest, Nyquil, Tide
    - Procter & Gamble Company, 1990-1998 (Box 10)
      Includes Crest, Crisco, Folgers, Pantene, Tide
    - Procter & Gamble Company, 1984-2008 (Box 12)
      Includes Crest, My Black Is Beautiful, Tampax, Tide
    - Procter & Gamble Company, 2005-2007 (Box 13)
      Includes Gain, Pure Essentials, Tide
    - Prudential, 1993-1995 (Box 9)
    - Prudential, 1993-1996 (Box 10)
    - Quaker Oats Company, 1993, 1995 (Box 10)
    - Quaker Oats Company--Aunt Jemima, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Sears, 1997-1999 and undated (Box 10)
    - Sears, 1997-2000 (Box 12)
    - Sony, 1992 (Box 10)
    - Sony--Sony Innovators Awards program, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Stroh Brewery--Schlitz Malt Liquor, 1986, 1997 (Box 9)
    - Stroh Brewery--Schlitz Malt Liquor, 1987-1990 (Box 12)
    - Stroh Brewery, 1984-1997 (Box 13)
      Includes Old Milwaukee, Schlitz, Schlitz Malt Liquor
    - Toyota, 2004 (Box 12)
    - Washington Mutual, 1998 (Box 10)
    - World African Network, undated (Box 10)
- General Files, 1958-2016 and undated; 2
  - 10th anniversary, 1981 (Box 14)
  - 10th anniversary album, 1981; 5 folders (Box 42)
  - 25th anniversary, 1996; 8 folders (Box 14)
  - Advertising Associations--Memberships, etc., 1990-2004 (Box 15)
    Memberships to AAAA, Chicago Advertising Federation (CAF), and Publicity Club of Chicago (PCC)
  - Approaches to diversity, 1993 and undated (Box 15)
    Includes presentation on multicultural marketing for Verizon
  - Awards--AAF Advertising Hall of Fame, 2004-2005; 3 folders (Box 15)
    Includes programs, photos, news releases, congratulatory letters, and an award from the Chicago mayor for Burrell's Induction
  - Awards--Advertising Hall of Fame Nomination Letter for Ed Lewis, Don Logan, 2007-2012 (Box 15)
  - Awards--American Institute of Architects, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Awards--Black Enterprise Magazine, 1995, 2010 (Box 15)
  - Awards--CAF Silver Medal, 1998 (Box 15)
    Press mentions, memos, and photos, see Burrell's acceptance speech in Box 34
  - Awards--CAF Windy Awards, 2000 (Box 16)
    Awards for McDonald's and Coca-Cola advertising
  - Awards--CEBA (Communications Excellence to Black Audiences), 1986-1992 (Box 16)
  - Awards--CEBA exhibit books, 1978-1983; 5 folders (Box 16)
  - Awards--CEBA exhibit books, 1984-1987; 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Awards--CEBA exhibit books, 1988-1991; 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Awards--CEBA exhibit books, 1992 (Box 19)
  - Awards--Chicago Mayor award for AAF Hall of Fame, 2005 (Box 19)
  - Awards--Circle of Excellence Award- Spelman College, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Awards--Clio, 1989-1990 (Box 19)
    P&G 1990 Tide commercial and for Media Partnership 1989 commercial
  - Awards--Communication Awards, 2003 (Box 19)
    Certificate of Achievement 2003 for Crest
  - Awards--Effie, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Awards--Miscellaneous, 1970-2012; 2 folders (Box 19)
    Includes The Chicago South End Jaycees Ten Outstanding Young Men of 1969, Chicago Business Hall of Fame, The Chicago Urban League Golden Fellowship Dinner, CAC Advertising Person of the Year, The Entrepreneur Hall of Fame, 51st Chicago International Film Festival TV Awards, Roosevelt University Commencement 2010, Loretto Hospital Foundation's Achievement Dinner; McDonald's Legend Award and Burrell's speech draft, DuSable Museum Certificate of Appreciation, Black Employee Network Pioneer Award, and Hurston/Wright Foundation Certificate of Appreciation
  - Awards--Miscellaneous, 2008-2014 (Box 42)
  - Awards--O'Toole Awards, 1998-2002 (Box 19)
  - Awards--Press, 1984-2015; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Awards--Superadio Network Award, 1996 (Box 20)
  - BC Good News (company newsletter), 1990-2002 (Box 20)
  - BCM-Fashion, 1993, 1998 (Box 20)
    Magazine spread of vintage African-American fashion from Upscale and Essence magazines
  - Black TV Producers Symposium, 1994 (Box 20)
  - Burrell Barometer, 1998-1999 and undated; 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Burrell letters to the Editor, 1993, 1996 (Box 20)
    Burrell's letters to the editor of Advertising Age on multicultural advertising
  - Burrell press releases, 1990-2000 (Box 21)
  - Burrell/Yankelovich African-American Monitor, 1992; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Chicago Urban League Golden Fellowship Dinner, 1981 (Box 31)
  - Clippings, 1971-1985 (Box 21)
  - Clippings--About Roosevelt University, 1958-1969 (Box 42)
  - Congratulatory letters, 2008-2015 (Box 21)
  - Howard Fellowship Project, 2008-2013; 2 folders (Box 21)
    Burrell Fellowship in Media Messaging; Board of Visitors
  - Howard Fellowship Project, 2008-2013; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Integrated Marketing Services (IMS), 1992 and undated (Box 22)
    Reports and company brochure on integrated market
  - LiveWire, 1999 (Box 22)
  - McGhee Williams Osse, 2008 (Box 22)
    Ebony Top African-American Women in Design
  - Media inquiries, 1998-2001; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Media literacy projects, 2011-2012 (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous notes on Burrell Communications, undated (Box 22)
  - Museum of Broadcast Communication Exhibit, 1994-1995 and undated (Box 22a)
  - "New World" Presentation, undated (Box 22a)
    Presentation and brochure on Burrell Communications' approach to marketing
  - Personnel--Staff lists and directories, 1980-1985 (Box 22a)
  - Photographs, 1977-2007 and undated; 2 folders (Box 22a)
  - Photographs, 1977-2007 and undated; 6 folders (Box 23)
  - Photographs, 1977-2007 and undated (Box 24)
  - Photographs, 2000s (Box 31)
  - Photographs, 1985-2004 and undated (Box 42)
  - Photographs--NBA All-Star weekend, 2001 (Box 24)
  - Publicis, 1999-2001; 6 folders (Box 24)
    Correspondence, press coverage and presentations of the Publicis merger
  - Published mentions, 1960, 1996-2011; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Published mentions, 1982-2010; 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Published mentions, 1985-1993; 6 folders (Box 25)
  - Published mentions, 1993-1996; 6 folders (Box 26)
  - Published mentions, 1996-1998; 6 folders (Box 27)
  - Published mentions, 1998-2000; 7 folders (Box 28)
  - Published mentions, 2001-2016; 4 folders (Box 29)
  - Published mentions--Framed article, 1984 (Box 31)
    "New Big Clients Put Black Agency in the Limelight" (Adweek)
  - Sarah Burroughs, 1990-2000 (Box 29)
    President and Chief Operating Officer of Burrell Communications. Includes memos on Burroughs' promotion and retirement, press mentions, photographs
  - Television historical lists, 1989-2004 and undated (Box 29)
    TV spots information for various ads including Coca-Cola and McDonald's
  - The Word, 1994 (Box 29)
    Black consumer market report
  - Young adult/kids marketing surveys, 1994-95 and undated (Box 30)
    Kids' monitor cereal survey, pamphlet on social concerns for young adults, undated survey
  - "Yurban" marketing concept, 2000 (Box 30)
    Memos, presentation, and photographs relating to the "yurban" marketing concept. Includes photographs of Fab Five Freddy, Sanji, and F. Gary Gary
- Presentations and Speeches, 1995-2007 and undated; 3
  - African-Americans and the Media Lecture Series, "Race Matters", 1996 (Box 34)
  - CAF Silver Medal Speech, 1998 (Box 34)
  - Capturing the Small Business Market1995 (Box 34)
  - Chicago Lighthouse Speech, 2007 (Box 34)
  - Columbia College Speech, 2005 (Box 34)
  - Notes and drafts, 1998-2003 and undated (Box 34)
  - P&G Minority Kick-Off Presentation, 2003 (Box 34)
  - Sears Multicultural Marketing Day, 2000 (Box 34)
  - "You've Got it Mass Backwards" speech to AAF, 1996 (Box 34)
- Book Files, 2000-2012 and undated; 4
  - Book-related speaking engagements, 2003-2011 (Box 34)
  - Brainwashed, 2009 and undated (Box 35)
  - Brainwashed--Book proposal, undated (Box 35)
  - Brainwashed--Contributions, financials, 2008-2010 (Box 35)
  - Brainwashed--Correspondence, contacts, 2008-2009 (Box 35)
  - Brainwashed--Email, transcripts, etc., 2009 (Box 35)
  - Brainwashed--International promotional tour, 2012 (Box 35)
  - Brainwashed--Manuscript and chapter drafts, 2009 (Box 35)
  - Brainwashed--Manuscript and chapter drafts, 2008-2009; 8 folders (Box 36)
  - Brainwashed--Marketing plans, 2008-2010 (Box 36)
  - Brainwashed--Notes, 2004-2012 (Box 37)
  - Brainwashed--Notes on media effects, 2002-2010 and undated (Box 37)
  - Brainwashed--Notes on race, slavery, and family, 2009 and undated; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Brainwashed--Procedural manual, 2009-2010 and undated (Box 37)
  - Brainwashed--Promotional tour, 2009-2010 and undated; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Brainwashed--Promotional tour, 2009-2010 and undated; 4 folders (Box 38)
  - Brainwashed--Quizzes, 2010 (Box 38)
    Thematic quizzes and questionnaires designed to accompany Brainwashed
  - Brainwashed--Tape transcripts, 2008 (Box 38)
  - Brainwashed--Tour and personal travel, 2010-2011; 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Brainwashed--Tour and personal travel, 2010-2012; 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Brainwashed--Website Development, 2010-2011 and undated (Box 39)
  - Brainwashed/Resolutions NAMLE (National Association for Media Literacy Education) conference, 2011 (Box 39)
  - Brainwashed/Resolutions theater initiative, 2009-2010 (Box 39)
  - Resolutions Project--Budget notes, 2011 (Box 39)
  - Resolutions Project--General notes, 2005-2011; 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Resolutions Project--Plans, proposals, etc., 2000-2012; 5 folders (Box 40)
- Personal Files, 1949-2011 and undated; 5
  - 65th Birthday card album, 2004 (Box 43)
  - Academic Files--Alpha Phi Alpha, 1960-1962 (Box 41)
  - Academic files--Papers, class notes, etc., 1951-1961 (Box 42)
  - Academic files--Parker High School, Roosevelt University, 1957-1961; 3 folders (Box 41)
  - Academic files--Ross School class photograph, 1949 (Box 42)
  - Roosevelt University newspaper, 1960-1969 (Box 41)
  - Personal photographs, undated (Box 41)
  - Philanthropy, 2003, 2011 (Box 41)
  - Scrapbook, 1974-1981; 5 folders (Box 42)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1971-2015 and undated; 6
  - AAAA O'Toole Award, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-001)
    Includes: Babies; Action Movie; Spicy Little Number; Guy and Girl; Twins; Directions; Girlfriends
  - BATA 85; tape 1 of 3, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-002)
    Ivanhoe Theatre; segments: The Blood of Jesus; Readings from My Diary part 3; Clean-Up Woman; Stubborn Love; The Marvoolus Marvoolettes; Girl Talk; Buc Wheet's Edition; Americanization; Burrell Update; Savvy Suits; Faces; Surprise Act; Finale
  - BATA 85; tape 2 of 3, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-003)
  - BATA 85; tape 3 of 3, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-004)
  - Bell Atlantic, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-005)
    Includes: Chandelier; Parrot; Yoga; Bread; Blowdry; Bubble Gum; Perfect World; Guess Who; Job Offer; Dr. Romance; Gospel
  - Clio Awards 40th anniversary reel, reel 1 of 2, 1999 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-006)
  - Clio Awards 40th anniversary reel, reel 2 of 2, 1999 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-007)
  - Coca-Cola commercial "Hilltop", 1971 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-008)
  - Coca-Cola USA Commercials--Hollywood Legacy, 1989 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-009)
    Includes: Seagrams Wine Cooler; Open Pit BBQ Sauce; Chevrolet Heart Beat; Jamaica Tourism; Stroh's; First Classes MCD; Family Reunion Ford; Marching Band CCUSA; Mr. Business Man MCD; Street Song; Kurtis Blow News Rap; Cameo; Run DMC; Minute Maid/Nique; Steppin
  - Mobil ethnic marketing video "Mobilizing the Community" 3:15, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-010)
  - Partnership for a Drug-Free America, 2003 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-011)
    Includes: The Enforcer; Watchers
  - Print ads master, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-012)
  - Schlitz Malt Liquor historical montage, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-013)
  - Soft Sheen creative presentation, I'm Beautiful, Dammit!; Luke's cut, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-014)
  - Tom Burrell Advertising Hall of Fame Video, 2005 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-015)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-016)
  - Video Monitoring Services Commercials, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-Umatic-017)
  - 25 Years of McDonald's TV, 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-001)
  - 25 Years of McDonald's TV, 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-002)
  - Coca-Cola: Always Coca-Cola pattern tape #1; 26:00, 1993 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-003)
  - Coca-Cola: Truth FM; 1:37, 2000 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-004)
  - CBS History Maker: Portraits in Color feature with Tom Burrell, 2003 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-005)
  - Different Drummers: WBBM-TV (CBS) Chicago; 30:00, 1997 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-006)
  - Hip Hop: The Newshour with Jim Lehrer; PBS-TV Network; 10:56, 1999 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-007)
  - Leslie Cole film transfer footage; 120:00 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-008)
  - Martin Luther King promo video; 3:00, 2004 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-009)
  - McDonald's: It's Showtime at the Apollo/Apollo Kids Winners; 62:50, 2002 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-010)
  - Millionaire, 1999 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-011)
  - MTV Cribs; MTV National 7:25, 2002 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-012)
  - Partnership for a Drug-Free America, 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-013)
    Inner city launch b-roll; TV message montage
  - Spelman College--Science Initiative revised; 8:26, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-014)
  - T. Burrell, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-015)
  - The Persuaders; PBS Frontline; WTTW-TV Ch. 11 Chicago; 1:20:00, 2004 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-016)
  - Tom Burrell interviews 5 reels tied, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-017)
  - Tom Burrell presentation, 2003 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11678-VHS-018)